MICHAEL ENRY DE GUZMAN

Software Developer

+1 778 859 7583

Surrey, B.C.

michaelydeguzman@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/michaelydeguzman

👩 github.com/michaelydeguzman

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, JavaScript, TypeScript, JQuery, CSS, ReactJS, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, Styled Components, KnockoutJS, AngularJS

Backend: C#, VB.NET, .NET Framework, .NET Core 3.1, .NET 6, .NET 7, ASP.NET & ASP.NET Core, Razor Pages

Data Access: Entity Framework & EF Core, Dapper

Desktop Application: WPF (Windows Presentation Foundation), Windows Forms

Tools: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, Azure DevOps, Jira, Github, TFS, Azure Dev Ops, AWS, S3, Azure Blob Storage, Postman

Database: SQLServer, MongoDB

Methodologies: Agile, Waterfall

Other Skills: Leadership, Communication, Collaboration, Problem-Solving, Project Management, Adaptability, Conflict Resolution, Mentoring, Innovation, Technical Documentation

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified Professional

Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: Web Applications

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer: App Builder

SUMMARY

I am a versatile Microsoft Certified Software Developer with 11+ years of experience in website, desktop application, solution integration & API development. Precision, quality, timeliness & innovation are the pillars I stand by as a developer in identifying challenges & implementing solutions within timelines to help drive business growth. These qualities have helped me achieve results either through effective collaboration within a team setting or working on independent projects. Eager to obtain a position to expand my learning and improve my developer skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

Centra Windows

O Langley, B.C., Canada

📆 06/19/2023 - Present

- Created a new Permissions application where developers & managers can control application & feature configurations for user permissions, access control, and login across all departments.
- Created a new Order management application to manage service & remake work orders. This allowed users to migrate from 3rd party application and allowed for more features & customization and reduce operation costs.
- Part of a team of 3 developers that upgraded the existing web calendar application to the latest stack. This added optimization & new UI/UX resulted in a 54% raise in productivity & day-to-day operations for users.
- Implemented a Rebate Calculator feature into main website which generated over 70 new leads for the Marketing team.
- Redesigned the Blog section & Quick search feature of main website which improved the readability of marketing content & increased site traffic by 25%.
- Part of a team of 3 other developers working on site that generates custom reports & dashboards to display data across different departments.
- · Redesigned and fixed bugs in current forms application.

Senior Software Engineering Consultant

BCS Technology International

NCR, Philippines

(iii) 09/2022 - 06/2023

- Full-stack developer for Rashays online ordering, call center, booking & inhouse reporting applications.
- Created & managed scheduled .NET console applications for POS EOB transactions.
- Managed REST apis for Rashays Mobile application in collaboration with React Native developer.
- Formulated solution approach & design for new membership website with new features such as Login, SMS verification & Rashays Wallet as an alternative payment method.
- Integrated ApplePay, GooglePay, Zip, and Stripe payment processors & gateways as alternatives to Credit card payment.
- Integrated DoorDash & Uber delivery partner APIS for online orders for improved customer experience.
- Managed & configured the PosAdmin Windows Forms app for menu updates & configuration across all branches.
- Migrated repos from Github to Azure DevOps and managed CI/CD releases to UAT and PROD via Azure Pipelines.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

Ateneo De Manila University Quezon City, Philippines 2008 - 2013

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Canadian Permanent Resident

REFERENCES

Andrea Kristina Oconer

(Former) Project Manager BCS Technology Int'l +61 493 319 999 (AU) +63 998 970 1903 (PH) andreaoconer@gmail.com

Serafin Encia Jr.

(Former) Tech Lead Barhead Solutions Inc. (Former) Tech Lead Pragmanila Solutions Inc. +63 968 888 7811 (PH) ssenciajr@yahoo.com

Kirsten Cilliers

(Former) Product Manager Simple.io, Australia +61 499 999 529 (AU) <u>cilliers.kirsten@gmail.com</u>

Technical Lead Software Developer

LP IT Solutions, Inc.

Q NCR, Philippines

11/2021 - 09/2022

- Full-stack developer for AU-based restaurant chain Rashays' websites for online ordering & reservation bookings.
- Integrated POS systems for different outlet restaurant operations (Pointsoft, Aigens, Lightspeed).

Technical Lead Software Developer

Pragmanila Solutions, Inc.

O NCR, Philippines

□ 04/2020 - 11/2021

- Full-stack developer for client project Simple V1.5 marketing legacy website.
- Migrated legacy website from v1 to new v1.5 version with code optimizations to back-end performance and better UI/UX experience for users. Also aided in infrastructure changes on the backend to allow multi-tenant deployment to load-balanced VMs in AWS.
- Full-stack developer for new DigitalAsset Management (DAM) website.
- Created SolutionApproach for challenges related to PDF & image file collaboration & markup, authentication & authorization, quality-of-life site features, cloud- storage, DB access, and ORM framework.
- Full-stack Developer for Local Area Marketing (LAM) website.

Senior Technical Consultant

Barhead Solutions Inc.

• NCR, Philippines

11/2017 - 04/2020

- Full-Stack developer for Simple HQ V1 SaaS marketing website
- Integrated PDFTron & WOPI document collaboration between users and for thumbnail generation.
- Implemented feature-flagging functionality for various web application features for easier development and business configuration.
- Created robust console applications for client data migration & extraction requests.
- Full-stack developer for the new Simple Local Area Marketing (LAM) website. Created Solution approach for challenges related to Epub to xHTML file conversion & upload, DOM nodes manipulation, HTML to PDF conversion, image/pdf cropping, resizing& scaling for print-ready output & digital asset cloud storage.

Associate promoted to Senior Software Engineer

Accenture Inc.

• NCR, Philippines

(iii) 05/2013 - 10/2017

- Developer & Application Support throughout the Open-C Project's major, minor & hotfix releases
- Developed and maintained console apps: scheduled EOB transactional batch jobs for charge calculations & meter readings.
- Wrote medium to complex scripts, stored procedures & VBScript extensions for in-house reporting & specific business charge calculation configurations.
- Integrated 3rd-Party service for Address Validation (QAS Pro).
- Created an in-house desktop application for Time-Entry tracking& reporting for project members.
- Developed VB.NET extension library methods for out-of-the-box business logic required by specific clients.